I'm ready now.
这样就准备完成了
I can bring down this building anytime.
随时都可以让这栋建筑物塌陷
I still have a lot of magic left.
我的魔力还很充足
At this rate, I can step in for Laios and the others if anything happens.
就算莱欧斯他们出了什么状况 我也能掩护他们
This plan is good, right?
这计划应该行得通吧？
I use up all my magic to stun the dragon.
比起将魔力耗尽 把龙弄昏
Instead of using chancy explosive spells against the dragon
赌上大家的性命 用不知道会不会中的
at the risk of everyone's lives,
爆炸魔法攻击龙
it's more reliable to bury the dragon in the debris of a building.
把龙压在建筑物底下会比较稳当
Yes, this is definitely a better plan.
绝对是这样做更好
Stay calm.
冷静下来
I need to focus on my task.
得专心执行我的任务
We'll make this work!
一定要让作战成功
Hang in there, Falin!
等着我们 法琳
DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宫饭》
It noticed us.
它注意到我们了
Run!
快跑
It's so fast!
好快
Just so you know, a Red Dragon's maximum speed is 60 kilometers per hour!
顺带一提 炎龙的最高时速是60公里
You should've said that earlier!
你早说啊
The terrain is slowing it down! It's all good!
可以用地形减缓它的速度 别担心
Turn right at the next corner!
下一个转角右转
We'll lure it to unleash its fire breath on this straight path.
在这条直路上引诱它使出火之吐息
Dragons breathe fire
龙会通过咂舌
by clicking their tongues to ignite the fuel stored in their bodies.
点燃积蓄在体内的燃料以吐出火焰
To prevent it from lashing out when we restrain it,
为了避免它在被困住时乱喷火
we'll make it use up all its fuel along the way!
要让它在路上就耗尽所有燃料
It's clicking its tongue!
是咂舌声
Here comes!
要来了
What intense heat!
多么炎热啊
But…
不过…
Thanks to this pot and magic, we can endure it.
幸好有锅子和魔法 还能撑得住
Good. So far, so…
很好 这下应该可以…
What?
这是怎样？
The heat of the pot is spreading evenly and…
锅子的热度平均地传导开来了
So hot!
好烫
But of course, it's hot!
当然会烫啊
Senshi uses it for cooking every day!
毕竟先西每天都用它来做菜嘛
Somehow, I thought it would have a special resistance to dragon fire.
我以为它会特别把龙火反弹回去
I thought Namari said
娜玛莉说过
that adamant protects against all dragon attacks.
精金可以用来抵御龙所有的攻击
She was just talking out of her hat!
那家伙是随便乱说的吧
I never said that.
我才没说
Ugh, it's doing it again!
糟了 龙又要喷火了
We have no choice!
别无选择
We'll change our route!
改变路线吧
Huh?
什么？
No way!
不会吧
They're here already?
他们已经来了？
Aren't they a bit early?
这也太快了吧？
Wait, what?
等一下 什么？
I thought the plan was to split in two!
要兵分两路的原定计划呢？
Can I go ahead and stick to the plan?
我可以照原先讲好的进行吗？
Ugh, I don't understand!
可恶 搞不懂
Fine! Here goes!
算了 我要动手了
No way!
不会吧
It's not hurt at all!
根本完全没伤到它嘛
Shh!
安静
Don't move.
别乱动
Its inverse scale is right there.
逆鳞就近在眼前
A few more steps, and I could reach it!
它只要再走过来一点就能砍得到
It…
那…
It ran away!
那家伙竟然逃掉了
Damn it, Kensuke!
可恶 剑助
Never trust a monster…
你终究是个魔物…
-You… -Laios! Chilchuck! Get up!
-你… -莱欧斯 奇尔查克 快起来
Above us!
在我们上面
Hide under its belly!
潜到它肚子底下
Laios, you bastard!
莱欧斯 你这混蛋
My bad! I'm sorry!
对不起啦 都是我不好
Dammit!
可恶
The common language doesn't have enough words of insult!
共通语可以骂人的词汇太少了
Ponza! Toroldo!
碰渣 拖罗多
-Unerma! Poojam! Varo! Monsanto! Belcher! -I'm being insulted in a strange language!
-乌逆马 朴扎木 巴漏 蒙桑斗 -他好像在用我听不懂的语言骂我
What are we gonna do now?
现在要怎么办啦？
It's angry! It's super angry!
它在生气 它现在非常生气
We have no choice.
没办法了
Let's run from the side of its tail--
只能从尾巴这端逃出去…
No, it's too dangerous.
不行 太危险了
What if we never manage to escape from under its crotch?
我们该不会一辈子 都逃不出它的胯下吧？
This won't do!
行不通
A simple incantation won't have any effect on it.
这么简单的咏唱对它无效
Focus!
得专心才行
What did you do that for?!
你在搞什么？
Our only weapon just got shattered!
我们唯一的武器粉碎了
What do we do now?!
接下来我们该怎么撑下去啊？
We have no choice.
不得已了
Use this.
用这个吧
What?
什么？
Is that really made of a special metal?
那果然是特殊金属打造的吗？
It slices through the bone and skin of every monster.
它可以切开任何魔物的骨头和皮
And I've diligently taken care of it each day.
老夫每天勤奋保养 从未懈怠
There's probably no other like it on this earth.
或许是世上独一无二的
It's a mithril cooking knife!
秘银菜刀
Mithril?
秘银？
Are you serious?
真的假的？
I wish Namari could've seen this.
好想给娜玛莉看看
Depending on the situation, she might've killed Senshi.
那家伙视情况搞不好会杀了先西
I had a suspicion that she might, which is why I chose to remain silent.
老夫也那么觉得 所以一直没说
Take this!
接招吧
It really pierced through its scale!
真的刺穿龙鳞了耶
But the blade is so short that no matter where I strike,
可是凭这刀身不管砍哪里
I might not be able to deliver a fatal blow.
都无法造成致命伤吧
What should I do now?
怎么办？
This means the plan failed, right?
这表示计划失败了吧？
Or are they executing a different strategy?
还是他们正在进行其他计划？
What am I supposed to do?
我到底该如何是好？
No time to hesitate!
没时间犹豫了
Get back!
往后退
My sword is getting farther and farther away.
离我的武器越来越远了
If we continue retreating, we'll end up in the open square.
再继续往后退会被逼到广场的
Then, we'll be turned to cinder by its fire breath!
到时候我们就会被火之吐息烧成焦炭
I will draw its attention.
老夫去引开龙的注意力
Don't! It's too risky!
不行 太危险了
Laios, you understand, don't you?
莱欧斯 你应该懂吧？
Among all the monsters you've eaten so far,
在你过去吃过的魔物当中
was there one that didn't give their utmost effort?
有哪个是没拼尽全力的吗？
In this place, it's a matter of eat or be eaten.
在这里不是吃 就是被吃
If we don't make desperate efforts, we'll be the ones who'll be eaten.
如果不全力以赴 被吃的就是我们
Brace yourself for the worst!
给我做好觉悟
Senshi!
先西
-Sen-- -Idiot!
-先… -笨蛋
There's no point if you rush out!
你跑出去就没意义了吧
Retreat for now.
你先给我退下
Figure something out with Marcille!
跟玛露希尔一起想想办法
Hey! Are you still alive?
喂 你还活着吗？
I'll help you out now--
我马上帮你移开…
Can you move?
你还能动吗？
I did it!
我成功了
It's stuck to the ground.
剑黏在地上了
Move aside!
闪开
Laios!
莱欧斯
I'll be right back!
我马上回来
Senshi! Get up!
先西 你快站起来啊
Sen--
先…
Sorry, Marcille.
抱歉 玛露希尔
I didn't expect to find you here.
没想到你在这里
I'm glad my magic seems to be working.
魔法好像还有效 太好了
What's going on? Where are the other two?
现在情况是怎样？另外的两个人呢？
Things aren't looking good.
状况很不妙
Every strategy we came up with has failed.
我们拟定的作战计划全失败了
The other two are unconscious at the dragon's feet.
他们俩现在昏倒在龙的脚边
What?! W-What do we do?!
什么？那该怎么办？
Right, the only option is to use my magic.
对喔 现在只能靠我的魔法
The dragon is injured and agitated.
龙因为受伤变得狂暴
It's risky to approach it or enter its line of sight.
随便接近它 或进入它的视野中都很危险
But we have to do something quickly!
可是得赶快想出办法啊
-Let's head upstairs. -What?
-到上面去吧 -什么？
W-What will you do?
要怎么做？
I'll climb to the height of the dragon's head.
先爬到跟龙的头等高的地方
-And stand inside the pot. -What?
-我会站在锅子上 -什么？
Then, I want you to blow it up.
然后你负责引爆它
What? Seriously?
你说什么？真的假的？
The dragon is blind in its left eye.
龙的左眼失明了
If I approach from its left side,
只要从左侧接近
I should be able to leap onto it without being noticed.
应该就能不被发现 跳到它身上
But…
那怎么行…
You did a similar maneuver before…
你以前也做过同样的事吧？
when you fought the Undine.
就是与水元素对战的那次
But that was on the water with Water-Walk.
那时候是因为有水和水上步行啊
This time, we have defense magic and the pot.
这次有防御魔法和锅子
What happens next?
那之后呢？
How will you stab its inverse scale while clinging to its head?
你抓着龙的头 是要怎么攻击逆鳞？
I have an idea about that.
那部分我自有打算
There's no room for more failures.
已经不容失败了
I don't plan on failing.
我不会失败的
Are you sure about this?
你确定要这么做吗？
You do have a plan, right?
你真的有想好对策吧？
I believe in you.
我相信你喔
I'll be flung off.
我会被甩下去
I need to execute my plan swiftly.
得快点执行对策
It'll be over in an instant.
才一瞬间而已
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的
Especially when compared…
跟法琳承受的疼痛相比
to Falin's pain!
这根本算不了什么
Laios!
莱欧斯
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I heard there's a ghost at the graveyard.
听说坟场有幽灵出没
Don't tell Dad or anyone else, okay?
不要跟爸爸他们说喔
-Whoopee!
-好耶
Don't worry.
别怕啦
It's difficult to walk with you clinging to me like that.
黏那么紧 很难走路耶
There's not even a single bug.
连一只虫子都没有
Let's head back, Falin.
回家吧 法琳
Laios…
莱欧斯哥哥…
Laios!
莱欧斯哥哥
Take it off!
帮我拿下来
Help me.
救救我
-Please. Take it off. -It's cold.
-拜托你 帮我拿下来 -好冷啊
I can't breathe.
我无法呼吸了
Falin, run…
法琳 快逃
Laios!
莱欧斯
Let my brother…
把我哥哥…
go!
放开
It's someone who was buried in that grave.
那个坟墓里的人
His ring is binding his soul.
灵魂被戒指束缚住了
Remove it for him.
帮他把戒指拿下来吧
And his soul will be set free.
他的灵魂就能因此解放
A ring?
戒指？
What are you talking about?
怎么回事？
This is the grave of Olman, who passed away recently.
这是欧尔曼的坟墓 他前几天去世了
When he was alive, he used to boast about a golden ring he bought from an elf.
他生前一直炫耀 从精灵那里买来的黄金戒指
How did that child know about it?
为什么那个小孩会知道这件事？
Did I do something wrong?
我做了什么坏事吗？
You're incredible, Falin.
你很厉害 法琳
You have a knack for ghost magic.
你有灵术的才能
Don't let it bother you.
别在意啦
Grown-ups are just scared of magic.
大人都很怕魔法
You should study proper magic.
你可以去好好学习正道的魔法
You'll never be out of a job.
这样就不愁没工作了
What kind of job?
工作？
Let's see.
我想想…
You could become a priest or a grave keeper.
可以当祭司或是守墓人
Being a traveling exorcist might be interesting, too.
四处旅行的除灵师好像也满有趣的
You travel to foreign countries, helping people in need.
周游各国 去帮助有困难的人
That sounds fun.
好像很好玩
If I do that, will you come with me?
哥哥 你也会陪我一起去吗？
Of course!
当然会啊
What country do you want to visit?
你想去什么样的国家？
I'd love to see the sea.
我想看海
Or even a desert.
沙漠也可以
They say there's a country of talking dogs in the desert.
据说沙漠中好像有个国家 里面有会说话的狗
I definitely want to go there!
那我一定要去
-But…
-可是…
maybe we shouldn't travel together anymore.
我们最好不要再一起旅行了
Falin, why not?
法琳 为什么？
You don't have to worry about me.
你不用再管我了
Goodbye, Laios.
再见 莱欧斯哥哥
Laios, are you okay?
莱欧斯 你没事吧？
I stopped the bleeding for now.
我先帮你止血
Just hold on a bit longer.
你再忍耐一下
I'll go look for the other two and for your leg!
我去找他们两个 还有你的脚
"Don't worry about me"?
“你不用再管我了”？
Don't say sad stuff like that.
不要说这么让人伤心的话啊
I promise to bring you back.
我一定会带你回去的
Hey!
喂
Chilchuck!
奇尔查克
Senshi!
先西
There you are!
找到了
Thank goodness!
谢天谢地
Are you okay?
你们没事吧？
Of course, not.
看起来很有事
I need to work on my defense magic more.
我也得多多练习防御魔法了
At least we haven't suffered any ruptures, so that's good enough.
至少身体没被撕裂 还算好的了
Tronsum Lunaae Stantinus Eurekant Oonzu.
托罗萨姆路那耶斯坦提努斯 幽雷亢特尤乌滋
Ow!
痛死我了
Isn't he in more pain now?
他是不是比之前更痛苦了？
When a serious injury is healed quickly, you experience recovery pain.
受那么重的伤 要在短时间复原当然会痛啊
Don't worry!
不用担心
It's a sign that you've healed properly!
这是痊愈的证明
It's your turn, Senshi.
接下来轮到你了 先西
I'm fine. I'll heal on my own.
老夫不用了 能靠自己治好
It could take months.
那要花上几个月啊？
Falin was skilled at recovery magic,
虽然法琳比较擅长治愈魔法
but I'm pretty confident in my speed as well.
但我对速度也是很有自信的喔
T-That's the cause of the pain, isn't it?
那不就是会痛的原因吗？
GAAAAAAH
（惨叫）
SNAP POP
（劈里啪啦）
Laios!
莱欧斯
Come on, lift your leg.
来 把脚伸出来
Britrayeums Lunae Actum Asbam Histum Eres Eurekant Ounzu.
布里托雷透乌姆斯路那耶亚克特姆 亚斯邦希斯特耶雷斯幽雷亢特尤乌滋
It reattached!
接上了
The inside of my leg feels itchy.
脚里面好痒
It's recovery pain.
因为在痊愈中啊
Well done, Laios.
你做得很棒 莱欧斯
You really defeated the Red Dragon.
竟然真的打倒炎龙
It's thanks to all of you.
多亏有大家帮忙
If any one of you weren't here, we couldn't have won.
少任何一个人都无法赢得这场仗
For a moment, I was afraid of what might happen.
一时间我真的担心死了
Even my blood froze.
老夫也吓到魂都飞了
Our estimate was a little too naive.
我们想得太简单了
Well, we won, so that's all that matters.
反正最后有赢就好了啦
But…
只是…
Here, Laios.
这个还你 莱欧斯
Kensuke.
剑助
I still haven't forgiven you for this yet.
关于这件事我可还没有原谅你
You owe me a long explanation.
待会给我好好解释
Right.
是
Well then, let's look inside its stomach.
好 来确认龙的腹中吧
What a thick skin.
好厚的皮肤
Fighting with this cooking knife,
难怪用菜刀跟它打
no wonder we couldn't even reach its subcutaneous fat.
也伤不到它的皮下脂肪
But it's going to be a lot of work getting to its stomach.
不过看来要切到胃得花费一番工夫
I could try blasting it open.
要不要由我来炸开？
The insides of a dragon are no different from any other creature.
龙的内脏跟其他生物应该是一样的
Let's slowly carve through its flesh.
还是慢慢把肉切开来找吧
It's one of its ribs.
这是肋骨
Let's go around it and keep digging.
稍微绕开再切除吧
It's dark. Should we light a lantern?
好暗 点个灯吧
No fire.
不能点火
Marcille, light.
玛露希尔 麻烦你照亮周围
It's so hot.
好热啊
It reminds me of when I used to work in a mine.
让老夫想起了在矿坑工作的时期
What's this?
这是什么？
It's the stomach!
是胃袋
All right.
好
Let's open it.
要割开了
It's empty.
里头是空的
It can't be…
怎么会这样？
Maybe we got the wrong dragon.
会不会是别只龙？
That's impossible.
不可能
The scar above its eye confirms it's the same dragon.
它眼睛上的伤跟当时的龙一样
It's difficult to imagine there being multiple territorial males in one area.
地盘意识强烈的公龙 不可能在这么近的距离内出现复数只
Let's examine its intestines as well.
为了保险起见 也找一下肠子吧
N-Not even a fragment of a bone is left.
居然连一根骨头都没剩下
We have to examine its droppings, too!
也得赶快去检查它的粪便
Could its digestion have been sped up by constant movement without sleep?
是因为龙都没在睡 一直在活动 所以消化得比较快？
I got it!
对了
What is this?
这是什么东西？
A mass of hair and bone.
是毛和骨头的结块物
Some creatures that ingest their prey whole
有些动物习惯一口吞下猎物
tend to regurgitate indigestible parts.
会把难以消化的部分 聚集在一起再吐出来
But instead of doing that, Red Dragons use them as fuel for their fire breath.
但炎龙不会将其吐出 而是当成火之吐息的燃料
These black hairs suggest it consumed a few Wargs.
看这些黑毛 推测是吃了好几头魔狼吧
And…
还有…
H-Hair…
是头发
Could it be…
那是…
Let's sift through the mass.
仔细扒开来看看吧
We might find human bones in it.
说不定有人骨混在里面
Hey, isn't this staff…
我说啊 这根棒子不就是…
Hey, Laios!
你看 莱欧斯
This staff!
这根魔杖
F…
法…
Falin?
法琳？
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻译：梁雪莹